Finding Aid for the The W. Whittier Wright Collection
Special Collections and University Archives
John Robert Nelson Papers
2005
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0598
Biographical/Historical Note
1941-1943 Attended Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee
1943 Received B.A. from Vanderbilt University
Scope And Content Note
The W. Whittier Wright Collection was a generous donation given to Special Collections by Mr. Wright in 1998. W. Whittier Wright is a graduate of Vanderbilt University, whose correspondence with Mr. Andrew Nelson Lytle began while Mr. Wright attended the University in the forties. The collection is contained in one half-sized Hollinger box.
Size 0.5 Linear Feet
Geographic Locations United States
Inclusive Dates 1943-1968
Bulk Dates 1947-1954
Languages English
Languages English
Summary Summary The W. Whittier Wright Collection came to Vanderbilt University Special Collections in 1998. Mr. Wright is a Vanderbilt Alumnus who graduated in 1943. His collection consists of correspondence between himself and Agrarian literary writer Andrew Nelson Lytle.
Access Restrictions No restrictions.
Copyright Consult Vanderbilt Special Collections
Stack Manuscripts Locations
- List Of Series And Subseries
  - Series I. Correspondence
    - Subseries 1. Outgoing
    - Subseries 2. Incoming
- Series And Subseries Descriptions
  - Series I. Correspondence, 1946-1968 (1 box)
  - The correspondence includes incoming and outgoing letters, spanning the years 1946 to 1968. The series is subdivided into Outgoing and Incoming Correspondence. Mr. Wright states in a letter to Vanderbilt University Special Collections that the correspondence shared between the two “speaks more to anecdotes of our friendship than it does to Lytle!’s writings...”
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Outgoing Correspondence:, July 28, 1946 – June 16, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing Correspondence:, July 7, 1947 – Dec. 2, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing Correspondence:, Feb. 3, 1948 – Dec. 9, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing Correspondence:, Apr. 29, 1949 – Oct. 25, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing Correspondence:, Nov. 25, 1951 – Nov. 25, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Nov. 7, 1943 – Oct. 26, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Mar. 31, 1945 – May 7, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Jun. 12, 1947 – Sep. 15, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Oct. 25, 1947 – Oct. 15, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Oct. 25, 1948 – Jun. 22, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Sep. 13, 1950 – Nov. 23, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Apr. 25, 1954 – Sep. 1, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)